David Bjerregaard Madsen

Borggata 6, 0650 Oslo +47 46825531 david.b.madsen@gmail.com

About me

Extroverted and ambitious software developer with an academic engineering background and broad spectrum of interests. I have 3,5+ years of professional experience developing solutions for a variety of clients, mainly in the Microsoft ecosystem.

Both during and outside of my professional career I have attained extensive experience working in and leading teams through numerous projects. Almost-daily contact with clients on every project I've been involved with has given me a good understanding of problem solving through understanding people. I value professionalism and set myself to a high standard in this regard.

I'm a curious soul and eager to attain new knowledge and improve my problem solving skills. In short, I am a highly motivated and driven developer who is eager to learn and meet new people.

Experience

February 2024 - to date

Uptime Consulting, Senior Consultant

Backend software engineer with expertise in .NET, cloud and distributed systems. Currently deployed at a fintech company delivering solutions to insurance and banking customers.

- Current project: Key part of the developer team at Lumera AS, developing a microservices-based .NET-application to manage fund trading, life insurance and pensions etc. for B2B banking customers.
- Responsible for core solution development and framework design where I have played a
 part in developing several microservices from scratch and a custom event-based
 messaging system for communication between microservices (Azure Service Bus)
- Responsible for code quality and review across the developer team

September 2021 - January 2024

Netcompany Norway, Consultant

Full-stack software developer consultant with main focus on .NET, EF Core, React, MS SQL and Microsoft Azure, with occasional dabbling into Python.

- Integral part of the developer team for a billing solution for a major toll service provider for the majority of the stay at Netcompany
- Responsible for backend development with occasional frontend tasks when required (Azure Functions, Azure Webapps, MS SQL, .NET Core, Entity)
- Devops tasks including CI/CD pipelines and deployment to development environments (Azure DevOps, Bicep)
- Responsible for coordinating and supporting both customer and internal test team on monthly releases

January 2022 - to date

Flux Collective AS, Co-owner & Technical Lead

Co-owner of a small Oslo-based electronic record label where I am involved in administrative and technical operations in the company.

- Develop and maintain the company website (<u>flux-collective.com</u>) and managing other business solutions
- Oversee financial planning, budgeting, and administrative operations

October 2020 - September 2021

Data Respons R&D Services, Development Engineer

Software developer/engineering consultant with focus on full-stack development and cloud solutions.

- Responsible for the web/cloud solution for our in-house GPS Tracker project (October-March) (Python/flask, websockets, React, GCP)
- Deployed as software engineer at a leading company in the automotive industry, assisting the engineering team with product validation, documentation and testing

August 2016 - October 2020

SplashTrend Licensing, Director of Digital Media - Freelance

Side project with study colleagues involving online media licensing, content production and promotion mainly on YouTube.

- Responsible for content acquisition and communication with social media users
- Video editing, branding and and visual content creation for our YouTube channels
- Developed proof-of-concept automated content recognition software to identify assets in online videos (Python)

Education

August 2018 - June 2020

Norwegian Uni. of Science and Technology, Industrial Cybernetics

- Master's degree in linear system design with electives in software development
- Master's thesis: Procedural City Generation in Unity Engine explored existing and new methods of procedurally generating cities using Unity Engine as the development platform (C#/Unity)

August 2014 - June 2017

Oslo & Akershus University College, Mechanical Engineering

 Bachelor's degree in mechanical engineering with electives in mathematics, computational fluid dynamics and robotics

Skills

Strong backend development skills, mainly experienced in the Microsoft ecosystem which I'm currently working with. In Microsoft Azure, I'm experienced with a wide variety of key cloud services including Azure Functions, App Service, Service Bus, Azure SQL, Cosmos DB etc. I am also well versed in other cloud providers such as AWS and GCP, and am able to cross-apply cloud knowledge accordingly.

I also to a lesser extent do frontend work mainly in React (js/ts), where I have experience from both professional solutions and side projects.

I'm comfortable utilizing other languages and platforms such as Python, where I have experience with web development frameworks such as Flask and asyncio. Outside of this I am interested in learning more about other less known languages and technologies, where I have explored both Rust, Golang and Elixir. I also frequently use Python to automate day-to-day tasks such as automating API calls, batch database operations, etc.

- Main languages: C#.NET, Python, JavaScript/TypeScript
- Languages I'm curious about: Rust, Golang
- Cloud: Mainly Microsoft Azure, but also familiar with AWS and GCP

- SQL/database: MS SQL/PostgreSQL, Azure Cosmos DB
- **DevOps:** Gitlab, Azure Devops, Github
- Other platforms, etc: Webflow, Wordpress
- Key words: .NET, distributed systems, cloud, backend development, full-stack

Certifications

- AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals (December 19, 2022)
- AZ-204: Developing Solutions for Microsoft Azure (September 21, 2023)

Languages

- Norwegian Native
- English Fluent

Interests

• Music Production & DJing: Regular performances at nightclubs in Oslo and hosting events.